Hi everyone, and thanks
for joining my talk today.
My name is Kemit and I'm a
software engineer at Uber on
the driver onboarding team.
I'll be speaking today about how
we transformed some of our existing
developer processes by utilizing AI
and creating various agentic workflows.
I'll go into a few use cases
that helped drive that developer
productivity on our team.
Below are some of the links
where you can find me online.
Let's go ahead and look
at the roadmap for today
We'll start off with some context
about the driver onboarding domain
and the entire problem space.
We'll then understand a bit more about
the domain, and then we'll look at
some developer workflow enhancements
created via AI that help to eliminate
some of the tedious processes and
help enhance developer productivity.
We'll then set the stage by understanding
the existing AI tooling and platform
architecture that exists at Uber.
We'll get a high-level understanding
of Uber's AI internal stack.
We'll then dive deep into our major
case study, the driver test-- the
driver onboarding test account AI agent.
We'll then cover guardrails
and evaluation criteria.
We'll then go over the quantifiable impact
that it had and the key takeaways that
you can apply on your own teams So to
understand why agentic workflows are even
a value-- are even valuable for our team
and service, let's first set the stage
for understanding more about the domain.
In a nutshell, driver onboarding is a
regulatory gateway to Uber's marketplace.
Before a driver can make money
engaging in the countless different
earning opportunities they qualify
for, they need to be successfully
onboarded onto the platform.
There's a ton of variables that go
into what makes a driver compliant,
but a few things to highlight are,
one, compliance and screening.
So this deals with being able
to coordinate criminal, motor
vehicle, and all of the background
checks with other vendors.
The second thing is earner
lifecycle management.
So this deals with tracking
earners pre- and post-activation.
The third thing is
multi-channel onboarding.
So this deals with supporting rideshare
couriers, fleets, and rental partnerships
across thousands of jurisdictions.
And lastly, identity and
document verification.
This includes validating driver's
licenses, registrations, inspections
with various adjudication checks.
On the right-hand side, we can
see some of the screenshots from
the driver onboarding funnel
So before we opted to integrate agentic
workflows into our larger systems and
processes, we turned AI agents toward
our immediate developer pain points.
When engineers first adopted coding
agents, we quickly ran into a wall,
and we were bottlenecked by the
fact that we could only operate on a
single branch in a single directory.
For example, if I had Agent A building
a UI component and an urgent data
science request coming in to update
some event metadata, traditional
Git workflows forced a bottleneck.
I would have to stop Agent A, stash
its work in progress, switch branches,
let Agent B run, and then pop the stash
later, forcing lots of issues, including
language servers to re-index and really
the agent to help rebuild its context.
To fix this issue, we built
an automated work tree skill.
The skill builds on top of the Git
work tree concept, which allows
you to check out multiple branches
of the same repository in separate
physical directories simultaneously.
This unblocked parallel
development and gave each agent
its own physical workplace.
Utilizing our previous example, Agent
A now continues generating UI code in
the primary directory while Agent B
executes the metadata fix in parallel.
Zero stashing, zero context
clobbering, and zero issues
In our next case study, we tackled
administrative gates that exist
in our pull request pipeline.
In our team, in our Uber enlarge pull
requests or what we refer to as diffs
at Uber, have rigid CI templates that
require explicit test evidence, link
tickets, and template-aligned summaries.
Early on, engineers used generic LLMs
to draft PR diffs, and the outputs
were exactly how you would expect it.
Verbose, missing required blocks, leading
to failed automated CI formatting checks.
To fix this, we fik-- we built a
deterministic branch to diff skill.
The agent ins-inspects the relevant Git
changes, extracts context directly from
Jira, verifies local unit test coverage,
and formats the diff summary precisely to
team guidelines, ensuring the diff passes
automated CI validation on the very first
attempt In our next mini case study, we
wanted to fix a-- we wanted to fix common
issues developers face, and that's the
good old soon-to-be outdated documentation
that we all love working with.
Am I right?
With agents, this issue is compounded.
An AI agent is only as good
as the context it retrieves.
In any engineering organization, we
are well aware that documentation
can quickly become stale.
In our own repository, we saw testing
documentation dating back to twenty
twenty-three to be completely misaligned
with how we're currently doing testing.
To solve this, we built an EngiWiki
sync, synchronization skill.
The skill automatically synchronizes
with our internal EngiWiki directly
with the current platform and
our code base as code changes.
It creates an automated single source
of truth and is always up to date.
So by guaranteeing that the agent
is grounded in the most up-to-date
documentation, we can have better
confidence that the right code
is generated on the first attempt
The last mini case study focuses
on how we improved our sprint
and task administration pipeline.
We all know that as engineers,
writing code is only half the job.
Engineers constantly break focus to
update tasks, and for the engineers in our
team, meant working with Jira, manually
creating tasks, filling out templates, and
updating ticket boards as work progresses.
To eliminate this context-switching
task, we built a dedicated rule that
manages the entire ticket life cycle
directly through the Jira REST API.
The agent automates lots of the
tedious administrative overhead,
like handling transitioning tickets
automatically, moving them into
various states when appropriate.
For example, moving a ticket to in
review when diffs are generated, and
also handling context and historically
related tickets by fetching historical
Jira tickets to pull relevant information.
So by offloading the ticket bureaucracy
to the API-driven agent skill, engineers
within the team were able to stay
in flow while also keeping project
statuses reflected of real-time status.
So before we can even talk about our
major case study, I do want to give a
high level view of the agentic tooling and
multi-layered infrastructure here at Uber.
At the foundation is the AI
platform, which is built on
top of Michelangelo, Uber Ma--
Uber's machine learning platform.
It provides the unified model
gateways, runtime runtime SDKs, and
a centralized agent registry Above
that sits context engineering, which
bridges models with internal Uber
reality through code context infra,
memory hierarchies, and the MCP gateway.
Above context engineering is the industry
and custom agents, which hosts both
external tools like Co-CloudCode and
internal SDLC agents for test generation,
code reviews, and background tasks.
And finally, at the top, we have
engineering enablement, which
governs cost, token telemetry, and
developer adoption across the org.
The two specific pieces of architecture
that are essential for the major
case study we'll talk about are the
agent builder and the MCP gateway.
The agent builder provides a standardized
environment for configuring and
deploying product-grade agents.
The agent builder provides
the following benefits.
It's a no-code solution, so the agent
builder provides an intuitive web-based
workplace where engineers, including
non-technical domain specialists, can
author, configure, and iterate on agent
behaviors using plain text constructions.
Next is native tooling
and MCP integration.
So instead of manually wiring API
clients, tools are first-class citizens.
And lastly is dynamic sub-agent handoffs.
Agent builders-- The agent builder
tool allows agents to seamlessly
hand off execution to other dedicated
agents, helping to preserve execution
context across the workflow.
The MCP gateway is the bridge between
our AI agents and backend microservices.
The MCP gateway acts as a proxy that
exposes microservices as standardized
tools, which is essentially
translating these internal RPCs
into a standardized MCP tool schema.
It also decouples agent logic, so
the agent queries schemas at runtime,
meaning API updates don't require
rewri-rewriting agent prompts.
And lastly, it contains built-in
observability and audit trails.
Now that we've introduced a larger
AI ecosystem at Uber, let's look at
one of our major test case study.
Let's look at our major case study,
the driver test account AI agent.
So historically, to test driver onboarding
features as well as reproducing bugs and
confirming existing flows, engineers and
other stakeholders needed to be able to
get accounts in their respective state.
However, the onboarding funnel
operates at global scale.
We operate across thousands of cities.
We manage dozens of earning verticals.
We have over fifteen plus background check
error states, dozens of document rejection
reasons, and so many other variables that
translate to more than fifty thousand
unique onboarding state permutations.
In our existing process, configuring a
single test account required following
multi-page run books, making manual
API crawl calls across many different
tools, which ultimately translated to a
minimum of five to ten minutes per setup.
To solve this, we sought to create
an agent-based solution that, with
a natural language prompt, could
facilitate the creation of the
test account in that exact state.
Underneath the hood, it's broken
down into a two-phased architecture
where phase one deals with just
base account test provisioning.
So in this case, we in this phase, we
create the base test account entity.
And in phase two, we transition that
base test account entity into the
exact state needed potentially calling
different services to to to have
the right requirement identifiers.
So for example, document
rejection states, background check
states, and so on and so forth.
The UI for this tool utilizes the
agent builder, and the MCP gateway
acts as the mediated layer or the
layer between the AI agent and the
downstream MCPs and microservices.
Okay.
And I want to talk about some
of the outcomes that we saw
after the launch of this tool.
So we saw a setup duration that
normally took anywhere from five to ten
minutes and at a minimum really drop
on, dropped to under thirty seconds.
We were able to achieve a ninety-five
percent end-to-end success rate
across our evaluation suites.
And lastly, we delivered a ninety-plus
self-serve generation access via
engineers, product managers, and other
ways in which the tool is used I now want
to wrap up with some of the takeaways.
So one, really being able to decouple
reasoning from any state mutation.
So we never want to force an LLM
to really be the manager of any
distributed microservice communication.
We really want to use the agent for
what it does best being able to map
parameters as well as take in any
dynamic intent translation in this case.
Once we have all that figured out, then
we want to be able to execute or hand
off that execution to a, a different
workflow that can better utilize
and get us into the correct state.
The second takeaway is being able
to let agents work in parallel.
So agents and agentic development is
it needs parallel needs parallelis-
parallelism in order to be enhanced.
It's really the bread and butter of how
we can supercharge our AI workflows.
As such, we wanna make sure that
we have a system or the right
configurations to allow that.
So whether it's using a Git worktree
style workflow or utilizing some of the
parallel agent features in some of our
favorite AI coding tools we really wanna
make sure that we're in a state where
we can let the agents work in parallel.
The third takeaway is being
able to benchmark tool calls
and not just vibe checks.
So really when building an agent
especially one that touches in multiple
parts of your back end or larger
infrastructure, we really wanna make
sure that we're using determinem--
deterministic evaluation metrics.
And lastly, safety belongs
in code, not in the prompts.
So a system prompt should never be subject
to any safety vulnerability and we want to
be able to enforce that as much as we can.
So of course there are always some
degree of security vulnerability.
You really wanna make sure you
patch up that or have the right
authorization or prevention tools
ideally potentially at the gateway layer.
And with that, thank you
so much for all your time.
Again, my personal links are on the
screen here, and I really hope to connect
with you folks in the near future.
Thank you.